Finding Aid for the June Wayne Papers LSC.0562
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1942-1997
  - Subseries 1: Business, 1942-1999
    - TR Miscellaneous, 1959, 1986, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      Correspondents include: Joyce Treiman re 1991 National Medal of Arts Nomination form for Wayne; Eduoard Trier re sculpture by Cornelia Runyan; includes photographic postcard of Notre Dame, Paris; Roberta Loach (Guest Curator, Triton Museum of Art, Santa Clara, CA) re invitation to Wayne to participate in exhibition, "The 500th Anniversary of Columbus' Discovery of America"; business card and flyer from Tram Way: Atelier de Tapisserie Base Lise, Lyon, France.
    - TH Miscellaneous, 1984, 1990, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Correspondents include: Michel Thomas (Director, Textile/Art/Language, Paris) re photographs of Wayne's work for book, "Textile Art"; Leonard R. Vignola (President and CEO, National Arts Stabilization Fund) re Wayne's contribution to memorial book honoring Marcia Thompson's retirement; Sandra A. Thompson re value of Wayne's lithograph "Burning Helix", which was lost in a fire.
    - Lucy Kuniko Kato, 1988, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Re Wayne's visit to Japan (1989 April.)
    - Tokoro Gallery, 1987-1993 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Correspondents include: Akiyoshi Tokoro (Tokoro Gallery, Japan) re article on Wayne; Kerry Tomlinson (Tokoro Gallery, Los Angeles) re visiting Tamarind in New Mexico, and exhibitions at Tokoro Gallery; also includes photographic holiday and greeting cards.
    - Book Inventory, 1969-1973 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Inventories and invoices for books, primarily Mary W. Baskett's "The Art of June Wayne" (1969), sent by Wayne to various people and institutions; also includes correspondence re Wayne's work and other biographical materials.
    - Boston Exhibition 1979 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      Correspondents include: Herbert A. Fox (President, World Art Exposition) re Wayne's participation in World Art Exposition (1979 September 26-30, Hynes Auditorium, Boston, MA); also includes World Art Exposition program.
    - Bowker Who's Who, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Correspondents include: Carole Kim re updating Wayne's biographical information for the 21st edition of "Who's Who in American Art."
    - Tabak/Rosenberg, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      Correspondents include: Harold Rosenberg and wife, May Natalie Tabak re Willem de Kooning 1968 retrospective at Museum of Modern Art, New York (MoMA); William S. Lieberman and the Tamarind show; list of names and addresses.
    - The California Art Review, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      Re Wayne's inclusion in the third edition of "The California Art Review."
    - UCLA Department of the Arts 1986, 1984-1986 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      Correspondents include: Jeanne Meyers re Wayne's participation in panel discussion, moderated by Josine Starels (1984 July 25, UCLA); Ruth Iskin (Program Specialists, Department of the Arts, UCLA Extension) re Wayne as guest speaker in lecture series, "Dialogues on Contemporary Art Issues" (1984 July 25, UCLA); Barbara Weinstock (Conference Coordinator, UCLA Extension) re Project Zero, and Wayne's participation in panel, "The Aesthetic Perspective: Can it be Developed and Transmitted" for conference, "Talent and Intelligence: Unlocking Creativity" (1986 November 1-2); also includes "Talent & Intelligence" program.
    - UCLA Center for the Study of Women, 1982, 1986, 1989, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      Correspondents include: Carole Magnuson (Public Information Representative, UCLA) re availability of tape of news coverage for Wayne's "The Dorothy Series"; Adele Scheele and Clarie Segal re UCLA Center for the Study of Women and invitation to membership tea; Cynthia Cooper (Assistant Vice Chancellor, Academic and Cultural Support Programs, UCLA) re invitation for Wayne to speak at California Concerns Fall Conference (1990 November 2); also includes documentation on University of California's Student Conduct Policy, "California Concerns" (bylaws, membership directory, meeting agenda), and copy of Wayne's speech, "Between the Last Word and the First Blow: Freedom of Expression as Experienced by an Artist."
    - UCLA Anni Albers Lecture Sept. 1986 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Re Wayne's participation in UCLA Art Council's symposium on Anni Albers (née Fleischmann, German-born American textile artist, 1899-1994, and wife of Josef Albers.)
    - UCLA Advisory Committee, 1973, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Includes paper by Ichak Adizes (Association Professor of Managerial Studies, UCLA), "The Cost of Being an Artist: An Argument for the Public Support of the Arts" (Research Paper No. 25, Management in the Arts Research Program, Graduate School of Management, UCLA) and reprint of article by Adizes and J. Fred Weston from Academy of Management Journal (vol. 16, no. 1. March 1973), "Comparative Models of Social Responsibility."
    - UCLA Grunwald Center, 1983, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Correspondents include: Karen Costello (Associate Coordinator, The Writer's Program, UCLA Extension) re Wayne's disappointment in extension class and request for refund; Lucinda H. Gedeon (Acting Curator, The Grunwald Center for the Graphic Arts, UCLA) re Wayne's participation in reception and catalogue for exhibition, "Tamarind: A 25 Year Retrospective"; also includes copy of Wayne's talk, and first draft (with edits) of the catalogue entry, "Tamarind: From L.A. to Albuquerque: A 25 Year Retrospective."
    - U Miscellaneous, 1981, 1982, 1984, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Correspondents include: Bill Ullman; Chris Unger; Melva Unter re Wayne's "The Dorothy Series" television program; Urs-Schuman Fine Arts Ltd. (Paula Schuman) re slides of Wayne's work; U.S. Post Office re Express Mail refund.
    - United States Customs, 1959, 1971, 1976, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Includes U.S. Customs forms and Certificates of Registration re exporting and importing Wayne's work.
    - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1992 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Correspondents include E.J. Montgomery (Program Officer, USIA - Arts America, Washington D.C.) re Wayne's attendance at reception honoring Earl Powell and J. Carter Brown at the National Gallery of Art, Washington D.C., and meeting to discuss possibilities of USIA's assistance in helping Wayne's retrospective exhibition travel to Japan, London, and/or Paris.
    - BA Miscellaneous, 1978, 1983, 1985-1987, 1989, 1992, 1994-1997 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include: Thomas E. Backer (Human Interaction Research Institute, Los Angeles, CA) re his articles and one-act play; Teresa Bailey re her marriage to Gary Johnson (includes wedding invitation); Mary Anderson Bain biographical information; James Barber (graduate student, University of Southern California) re discussing Wayne's arts-advocacy activities; Claude Bardin re meeting Wayne at a conference; Will Barnet; Max (Robert) Barrett (Director/Chief Curator, Fresno Art Museum) re Rush Limbaugh, Barrett's application to Big Brothers of Greater Los Angeles, and Wayne's computer problems; Patricia Barrow (Curatorial/Education Assistant, Newport Harbor Art Museum) re returning Wayne's slides and catalogues; Ivy L. Barsky (NEA Curatorial Intern, Department of Prints, Drawings and Photographs, Philadelphia Museum of Art) re exhibition, "Women's Work: American Printmakers of the 1930s" and the work of Shirley Julian; Norma Bartman re Wayne's speech given at Hofstra Museum, Hofstra University Conference on The Avant-garde in Literature and Art (1985 November), Long Island; Gregg and Cathy Bayne photographic holiday card depicting Frederick Lightfoot Bayne.
    - Hadid, Zaha, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Includes Hadid's curriculum vitae, one 7 x 9 inch black and white photograph of Hadid, three color slides, and two articles on Hadid's work.
    - Hofstra University, 1985-1987 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Correspondents include: Barbara Lekatsas (Coordinator, Avant-Garde Art and Literature Conference, Hofstra University Cultural Center) re Wayne's participation in the conference; performance of Picasso's play, "Catch Desire by the Tail"; also includes edited copy of Wayne's speech, "Avant-Garde Mindset in the Artist's Studio" given at Hofstra University Conference on the Avant-garde in Literature and Art; and conference program.
    - Hillsdale College (Trip), 1985-1987 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Correspondents include: Joseph S. McNamara (Vice President for External Affairs, Hillsdale College, MI), Lissa Roche (Director of Research), and Sam Knecht (professor) re Wayne's lecture, "View from Inside the Outside" in the Center for Construction Alternatives seminar, "The Dream and the Deal: The Arts After FDR" (1987 February 8-12); also includes poster and transcript from Wayne's talk, "Inside the Outside: An Artist's New Deal Heritage", two issues of the Hillsdale College publication, Imprimis, a brochure on Hillsdale College and President's Report (1985/86), and brochure for Henry Bernsteain exhibition, "Paintings, Drawings & Mural Studies" (1986 October 26-November 22, Arnold Klein Gallery, Royal Oak, MI.)
    - Los Angeles Task Force On The Arts, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Contains Morris McNeill, Inc. draft report, "The Los Angeles Cultural Masterplan" submitted to the City of Los Angeles Cultural Affairs Department (1990 November.)
    - Los Angeles Task Force On The Arts, 1986, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Correspondents include: Laurie Garris (Project Administrator, L.A. Task Force on the Arts), Barbara Goldstein (Deputy Director), Michael Pittas (Executive Director), and Karen Hill-Scott and Alice Walker Duff (Morris McNeill) re Wayne's participation in the L.A. Task Force on the Arts, and the Arts Advisory Committee work; includes correspondence, meeting minutes, and summaries.
    - Coleman, Lee & (sisters) Judith & Manny Zane, 1955, 1980-1982, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      Re Lee Colman's health issues, Wayne's litigation, "The Dorothy Series" tour, and catalogue of Wayne's exhibition at Fresno Art Museum; also includes three black and white 2.5 x 3.5 inch photographs and Atlantic City photobooth photograph of members of the Zane family.
    - Victoria Paper Company, 1981, 1992, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Correspondents include: Aimee Kligman (President) re the National Arts Materials Trade Association (NAMTA) Conference in Las Vegas (1992 May); Victoria Paper Company paper samples; Wayne's speech at W. McNeil Lowry memorial (1993 September 27, Lincoln Center Plaza, New York); also includes press releases and articles about Kligman and the paper industry; four issues of Victoria Paper Company's "Paperceptions" newsletter (1992 January, June, and October; 1993 April.)
    - Associated American Artists Show New York 1988, 1986, 1988, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Correspondents include: Lillian Berkman; Robert Conway (Director) re Wayne's print, "Witnesses", price lists of Wayne's work, shipping lists, exhibition of Wayne's work, print dealers in Chicago, Arlene Bujese, Wayne's trip to Japan, Wayne's speech at College Art Association (CAA) Conference in New York (1990 February); Susan Teller; also includes clippings from New York Times advertising Wayne's lithographs from the "Djuna Set."
    - New York Show Lists, Sign of The Dove, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Includes lists of "Collectors and Personalities," artists, and dealers with names and addresses.
    - Mailing Lists for Show, Nov. '73 Barnsdall Park. Master, 1969, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Includes press release and mailing lists for invitations to Wayne's exhibition at the Municipal Art Gallery of Los Angeles, Barnsdall Park (1973 October 30.)
    - New York Show List 1969. Far Gallery. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Includes mailing lists for invitations to Wayne's exhibition at the FAR Gallery, New York (1969.)
    - New York Show List, Master List 1969 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Master mailing list of collectors, personalities, and dealers.
    - Kentucky Miscellaneous Museums, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Correspondents includes: Theodore J.H. Gusten (Executive Secretary, Print Council of America) and John Harris (Director, J.B. Speed Art Museum, Louisville, KY) re edition numbers for Wayne's pair of prints, "Adam" and "Eve" in Speed Museum.
    - California Palace Legion of Honor Calif., 1950-1953, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Correspondents include: Jerry Maclegg (Orbit Films, San Francisco; California Palace of the Legion of Honor) re visiting Wayne, Wayne's comments on Rico LeBrun's exhibition; Thomas C. Howe, Jr. (Director, California Palace of the Legion of Honor, San Francisco) re including Wayne's painting, "The Sanctified" and painting by William Millarc in 5th Annual Exhibition of Contemporary American Painting; exhibition catalogue; inclusion of Wayne's print, "Last Chance" in Philadelphia Print Club "Curator's Choice" exhibition (1956.)
    - Joan of Art List - other women, no date (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Contains name and address list for four "Joan of Art" seminars (1970s.)
    - Register of Women Artists, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Contains "Register of Women Artists" compiled and edited by Connie Jenkins with the assistance of Vaughan Kaprow from the Women Artists' Slide Collection, California Institute of the Arts, Valencia, CA; published by the Feminist Art Program, Miriam Shapiro (Director.)
    - Artists Councils of the Arts ACA Mailing List, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Contains photocopy of Wayne's personal address book; Associated Councils of the Arts (ACA), Delegates' List to 1975 Annual Meeting, Cleveland, OH, July 10-12.
    - Washington: Miscellaneous Museums, Art Institutes, Studios, Etc., 1963, 1966-1970 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include: William Matheson (Chief, Rare Book Department, Washington University Libraries) to Orrel P. Reed re receiving copy of Wayne's exhibition catalogue, and decline to purchase Wayne's "Songs and Sonets of John Donne"; Lois A. Bingham, Barbara Fendrick, and Robert Sivard (Fine Arts Section, Exhibitions Division, United States Information Agency) re purchase of Wayne's prints, "Adam and Eve" and "Tower of Babel #A"; Frances Smyth (Program Assistant, Traveling Exhibition Service, Smithsonian Institution) to Wally Dunbar (Tamarind Press) re loan extension for Wayne's print "At Last a Thousand III" in Library of Congress traveling exhibition, "20th Print National"; Prentiss Taylor (President, Society of Washington Printmakers) re Wayne's recent exhibition, Tamarind exhibition at Museum of Modern Art, New York, making Wayne an Honorary Member of the Society and including her print, "The Tenth Memory" in a future show; Jacob Kainen (Curator, Prints and Drawings, Smithsonian Institution, Washington D.C.) re visiting Wayne's studio, Kainen's departure from the Smithsonian and his successor, Janet Flint.
    - Los Angeles Art Committee Calif., 1954, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Correspondence re controversy over installation of Bernard Rosenthal bronze sculpture, "The Family Group" in front of the Los Angeles Police Facilities Building and creation of the Los Angeles Art Committee (founded 1955 February 7); includes Wayne's letters to the editors of the Los Angeles Mirror, Daily News, Los Angeles Times, as well as Los Angeles City Council, Board of Public Works, Municipal Art Commission, and Canyon Crier; other correspondents include Mrs. Hoffman, Marguerite Scully Fanning, Faie Joyce, Hugh Tiner, John S. Gibson, Jr. (President, Los Angeles City Council), and Earle D. Baker; also includes City of Los Angeles Resolution (1954 August 16) issued by Earle D. Baker (Councilman, Second District) re removal of the sculpture; March 1955 issue of Frontier magazine with article on Rosenthal controversy by Jules Langsner, "That Police Building Statue" (pp. 20-21.)
    - State of Cal. Conference on Good Design, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Correspondents include: Edmund G. Brown (Governor of California, 1959-1967) and John H. Stanford (Vice Chairman, Governor's Conference on Good Design) re Governor's Conference on Good Design (planned for early December 1964); also includes projected conference outline.
    - People to People Office of the Mayor Correspondence, 1962, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Correspondents include: Karl L. Rundberg (Los Angeles City Councilman, 11th district, 1957-1963) re formation of the Nagoya-Los Angeles Sister Committee; Mayor Sam Yorty (Mayor, Los Angeles, 1961-1973) to Honorable Kiyoshi Sugito (Mayor of Nagoya) re four students from Sakuradai High School visiting Los Angeles, and May Sugito's visit during Los Angeles Nisei Week Festival (1962 August 9-20); Frank P. O'Sullivan (Assistant to Mayor Yorty) re Los Angeles-Salvador Sister Cities Committee and Los Angeles-Nagoya Sister City Committee general election meeting; also includes: "News Memorandum" from Mayor Yorty on proposed trade-stimulating programs for 1962-63 budget; People-to-People Program "Sister city Committee Procedure."
    - Pacific Arts Association Arizona, 1955, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Correspondents include: Ray Fink (Associate Professor of Art, Pacific Arts Association) re reproducing Wayne's drawing in PAA bulletin; Dorothy J. Begarmo (Director, Phoenix Fine Arts Association) re Wayne's possible participation in Solar Energy exhibition (1955 October 17-November 16) in coordination with the World Symposium on Applied Solar Energy, Phoenix, AZ; also includes symposium brochure.
    - Eric Locke Gallery, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      Correspondents include: Eric J.H. Locke (owner) and George Sweeney re including Wayne's prints and prints from members of Tamarind Lithography Workshop in exhibition of California Printmakers.
    - Art Other than Painting, Prints, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Correspondents includes: Rhea Laskin Wachsman to Wayne re help in acquiring support for establishing a social and jazz dance film library; also includes copy of Wachsman's letter to W. McNeil Lowry (Director, Center of the Humanities & Art, Ford Foundation) with her foreword, and a brochure for her "Dance through the Ages" lecture-dance.
    - California State Fair, 1953, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      Correspondents include: E.P. Green (Secretary-Manager, California State Fair) re Wayne's being selected to contribute a print for the 1953 "Art and Good Design Exhibition"; Wayne's print, "Study for a Messenger" being awarded honorable mention in the State Fair's 1955 Art Competition; Wayne's participation in meeting of the Artists Advisory Board (1957 February 5, Los Angeles County Museum.)
    - Salzer Galleries Calif., 1958, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      Correspondents include: Maria and Oscar Salzer (Salzer Galleries, Los Angeles, CA) re sales results of Wayne's work; Wayne starting work on portfolio for poems of John Donne; Wayne's contract with Zeitlin and Ver Brugge to handle world distribution on her book; also includes sales receipts and invoices for Wayne's work sold by Salzer Galleries.
    - International Student Center Calif., 1963 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      Correspondents include: Arthur Millier (Co-Chairman Pro Tem, Art and Music Friends, International Student Center) re Wayne agreeing to serve as member of founding committee for the Arts and Music Friends of International Student Center; also includes brochure on the Center and list of committee members.
    - California Miscellaneous Museums, Art Institutes Etc., 1961-1965 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      Correspondents include: Jarvis Barlow (Director, Los Angeles County Art Institute [interim name for Otis Art Institute]) re Wayne's participation in exhibition "Contemporary Religious Art" by Southern California Artists (1960 December 15 - 1961 January 15); Millard Sheets (Director, Otis Art Institute) re Wayne's participation in annual print exhibition (1962 and 1963); Mrs. Franklin V. Walker (Program Chairman, Art Department, Pomona College, Claremont, CA) re Wayne speaking to members of the Rembrandt Club (1963 January 17); Dr. Donald W. Schafer (Pasadena, CA) re Wayne's book, "Songs and Sonets of John Donne"; Sylvia Meller (Zeitlin & Ver Brugge Booksellers, Los Angeles, CA) re exhibition catalogue "Printing and the Mind of Man" (1963 July 16- 27, British Museum, London), Wayne attending the Book Fair, and Wayne's message to Jake Zeitlin about John Donne; Miki Benoff (Beverly Hills, CA) re sending material to Pete Pollack; Shibley Bayes (Los Angeles, CA) re her hand-made cards and Wayne's suggestion for her to contact the Joseph Press; William Firschein (artist) re Wayne's help, representation at Ankrum and Salzer galleries; Robert Logan and Robert Cugno (Yorkshire Antiques, Santa Ana, CA) exhibiting Wayne's work at their newly opened Contemporary Arts and Crafts Gallery; Felix Landau (Los Angeles, CA) re article in Art Forum; H.C. Schwarm (Associate Professor of Art, San Fernando Valley State College, Northridge, CA) re request of Wayne to speak at college lecture series; Glen Burch (Director, University Extension, University of California, Davis) re Wayne's lecture at workshop, "Original Prints and their Place in the Art of Today" (1965 November 18); William Goodman (Gallery Assistant, San Francisco Art Institute) re price and availability of Wayne's prints, "Dorothy the Last Day", "Dead Center II" and "Tenth Memory" included in exhibition, "California Printmakers."
    - Koslow-Gleaves Gallery, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      Correspondents include: Beverly Kozlow-Gleaves (Kozlow Gallery, Encino, CA) re Wayne's possible participation in venture corporation, American Graphic Arts, whose function would be as a national retail outlet for American graphic artists; Wayne declined.
    - Mt. San Antonio College, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      Correspondents includes: Richard L. Raynard and Carl Kniting (Co-chairmen, Bijutsu, San Antonio College, Walnut, CA) re Wayne participating in convocation lecture and loaning her work for exhibition during Bijutsu Shukujitsu, the college's Fine Arts Feast.
    - Art Rental Gallery of the Junior Art Council of the L.A. County Museum. Calif., 1953-1956 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      Correspondents include: Mary Griffith (Chairman, Art Rental Gallery) and Virginia S. Weaver (President, Junior Art Council) re details of Art Rental Gallery functions (established October 1953); other correspondents include Grace E. Boles, Jeanette Garnier, Priscilla Maughan, Phoebe L. Leiby, Aileen B. Lumley (treasurer), Dorothy Sherwood, and Lillian Weiner re Wayne consigning various works to the gallery.
    - Correspondence with European Galleries and Museums, 1971, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      Re Wayne seeking representation/exhibitions of her work in Europe; correspondents include: Bibliothèque nationale, Brussels; Galerie d'art modern (Jeanne Wiebenga), Lausanne; Victoria and Albert Museum, London; other correspondents include: Alfredo Paglione (Milan); Franz Larese (Galerie im Erker, St. Gallen, Switzerland); Rudolf Raubach (Kunsthandlung, St. Gallen, Switzerland); Galerie Renée Ziegler (Zurich, Switzerland); Edwin Engelberts Galerie d'Art (Geneva, Switzerland); Dr. Fritz Nathan (Zurich); Dr. H. Von Matt (Zurich); Kupferstich Boutique (Zurich); Galerie Gérald Cramer (Geneva); Anlikerkeller Bern (Bern, Switzerland); I. Auerbach (Neue Galerie, Zurich); Socrate (J. Spoorenberg, Bienne, Switzerland); M. Flury (Kunsthandlung, Bienne); Galerie Daniel Keel (Zurich); Gallerie d'Arte Moderna (Milan); Dr. Andreson (Lausanne, Switzerland); Galerie Wolfgang Ketterer (Munich, Germany.)
    - John Donne Book Correspondence, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 22)